<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
  <rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>Anthony DeSouza - Articles</title>
      <description>A personal blog with a focus of data science, machine learning, and other software experiments</description>
      <link>
      https://desouza.li</link>
    <item>
      <title>Optimization Using Genetic Algorithms</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Whether it’s minimizing manufacturing costs, finding the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Travelling_salesman_problem&quot;&gt;shortest path around a city&lt;/a&gt;, or finding an optimal airfoil design, optimization problems are everywhere. An &lt;strong&gt;optimization problem&lt;/strong&gt;, simply put, is the problem of finding the &lt;em&gt;best&lt;/em&gt; solution from all feasible solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
      </description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2017 04:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <link>
      https://desouza.li/genetic-algorithms</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://desouza.li/genetic-algorithms</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Minifying Jekyll Content on a Shared Host</title>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;I love &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. It makes it super simple for me to create the content for this site. All I have to do is open up a text file and start typing. When I’m done, it’s just a simple &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git push&lt;/code&gt; away from the web where it’s formatted and compiled into static files.&lt;/p&gt;
    </description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <link>
    https://desouza.li/jekyll-minify-on-shared-hosting</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="true">https://desouza.li/jekyll-minify-on-shared-hosting</guid>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Pentax Firmware Decrypting in the Web</title>
  <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of years ago, I purchased my first DSLR: the Pentax K-30. Photography has been my hobby ever since, and I’m always looking for cool new things to push my camera further. The one thing that I really miss from my previous Canon point-and-shoot is unsurprisingly, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://chdk.wikia.com/wiki/CHDK&quot;&gt;Canon Hack Development Kit (CHDK)&lt;/a&gt;. Luckily, most of the features that make it so useful, such as RAW image capture, live histogram, and the intervalometer are already present in the K-30. I’m not missing out on much.&lt;/p&gt;
  </description>
  <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2015 18:40:00 -0500</pubDate>
  <link>
  https://desouza.li/pfwtool_html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://desouza.li/pfwtool_html</guid>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>